shoeaholics.com 2019-01-14

# Shoeaholics | Cookies & Privacy Policy

**Cookies & Privacy Policy **

This Privacy Notice and Policy sets out how we approach handling our customer personal information. We want our customers to feel confident your personal data is secure and understand how it is used. The important things to be aware of from the outset are that

• We ask for what we need - The information we collect from you is based on the necessary information to fulfil your orders, and present you with relevant products & news.  
• Keeping it safe - We have processes in place to keep your data safe. We don’t store your payment card numbers.  
• We never sell your data and share it carefully - We don’t sell your data to third parties. We do use carefully selected service providers to support fulfilment, payment processing and marketing.  
• Unsubscribing from direct marketing is easy – click unsubscribe or contact our customer care team.  
We would be happy to deal with any data protection queries you may have, please contact us at customerservice@shoeaholics.com in the first instance. 

**Privacy Policy**

Kurt Geiger Limited ("we" and "us") collects, processes and is responsible for personal data relating to our customers, those interested in our products and others. Our use of personal data is regulated by data protection laws, particularly the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which applies across the European Union. We are responsible as ‘controller’ of that personal data for the purposes of data protection legislation.  
We are a limited company with our registered office address at 24 Britton Street, London, EC1M 5UA and company number 00968046. We are registered at the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) (www.ico.org.uk) and our registration number is Z6823882.  
This Privacy Notice and Policy applies to all processing of customers’ and potential customers’ personal data by us and our affiliated companies.

## WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT AND USE?

  * **Identity Data** , includes your name, username or similar identifier and gender.
  * **Contact Data** , includes billing and delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Transaction Data** , includes what you bought, when, and the delivery method.
  * **Payment Data** – All payment processing is handled by Sage Pay or Paypal, so we do not collect, store or process your payment card number. We do however collect information about the payments, orders and purchases. In exceptional circumstances to process refunds we require bank account details for refund handling. 
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** , includes your feedback, communications you have sent to us or we have sent to you, preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences.

We collect the following data automatically using cookies and other similar technologies: 

  * **Technical Data** , Technical data includes details your visits to our sites including web pages viewed and search terms entered, internet connection, device and browser settings as well as the internet protocol (IP) address and location.
  * **Usage Data** , includes how you use our website and communication engagement (including email and social media). 

We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy for further details.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH PERSONAL DATA AND OUR LAWFUL BASIS FOR DOING SO**

We process your personal data for the following purposes:

Purpose | Data Processed  
---|---  
To process your order, take payment, fulfil and process returns to fulfil a contract we have entered into with you | Identity, Contact, Transaction, Payment  
Our legitimate interest to identify potentially fraudulent orders | Identity, Contact, Payment, Technical  
Our legitimate interest to market to you and provide website personalisation | Identity, Contact, Transaction, Marketing and Communications, Technical, Usage  
Our legitimate interest to generate management information & provide customer service updates | Identity, Contact, Transaction, Payment  
Our legitimate interest to monitor web traffic and usage analytics | Technical, Usage  
With your consent when using the Store | Technical  
  
The lawful basis for processing data for these purposes is:

• To fulfil a contract we have entered or are about to enter into with you.  
• Where it is in our legitimate interest and your interests do not override that interest.  
• To comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.  
• When you have given consent to process your information.  
Where we rely on consent then you may withdraw that consent at any time.  
Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data. 

**Google Earth**  
We process your personal information with your consent when you use the Store Finder functionality of our website. This is provided by the Google Earth service, hosted in the US. To provide this service, Google need visibility of your IP address to determine your location. You have the option to provide the website, and Google, with your location information. You can opt out of Google by removing permissions to the map in your browser. 

Google provide a separate [Terms of Service](http://www.google.com/help/terms_maps.html) which provides more information. 

**MARKETING**  
If you have asked us to, are a customer or you have approached us regarding similar goods and have not unsubscribed or opted out we may send you marketing communications.

Each time we send you a marketing communication we will give you the opportunity to opt out of this marketing. You may also opt out of marketing by contacting customerservice@shoeaholics.com.

If you do opt out we will stop sending you marketing communications but will continue to send you service communications directly linked to the processing and fulfilment of your transactions with us.

To keep you aware of what we are up to and to help you see and find our products we also engage in online advertising, including banners and ads, when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges.

## WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH

We share your data with carefully selected partners who fulfil core business processes for us (including order fulfilment and marketing) as set out below. All third parties are checked to ensure they can provide sufficient guarantees regarding the protection of your information, and we have written contracts with them which provide assurances around the security and handling of your information and compliance with our data security standards. 

Third Party | Connected Activity  
---|---  
Email Service Providers | Marketing communications  
Web session analytics provider | Customer Analytics  
Google Inc. | Store Finder  
Fraud prevention service | Fraud prevention and detection  
Courier service providers | Order Delivery  
IT hosting and service providers | Hosting and supporting our IT infrastructure  
  
Some of the personal information you provide to us may be transferred outside the European Economic Area to the US. This is due to our use of cloud services provided by Google and Mailchimp at this time. Where this is the case, we only use third parties where there are appropriate assurances of data protection, for example both MailChimp and Google are compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

We will share personal information with law enforcement or other authorities if required by applicable law.

We will not share your personal information with any other third party.

## DO YOU HAVE TO PROVIDE US WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

The provision of certain Identity, Contact, Transaction and Payment Data is required from you to enable us to process and deliver your order. We will highlight at the point of collecting information from you, the data which is required for this purpose.

## DATA SECURITY

The security of your personal information is very important to us, so we take the utmost care and all appropriate steps to protect it.  
By default, all browsing on our website is encrypted. All payment-related traffic is encrypted directly between you and your chosen payment provider. Our websites do not see this interaction.  
Access to your personal information is password protected and all systems are monitored to identify possible problems. 

## HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR DATA FOR?

We assess the retention period of data on the basis of a number of factors. The specific retention period will vary according to the reason for processing your personal data and laws and regulations. 

## YOUR RIGHTS

Under data protection laws, in certain circumstances you have rights relating to your personal data as follows: 

• Request access (a "data subject access request"). This allows you to obtain a copy of the personal data we hold about you.  
• Request correction of personal data that we hold about you.  
• Object to processing, if we are relying on a legitimate interest if you feel the interest impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms.  
• Request erasure, enabling you to ask us to delete personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where: you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing; we have processed your information unlawfully; or we are required to erase your personal data to comply with the law.  
• Request restriction of processing, in certain circumstances, to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data.  
• Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at customerservice@shoeaholics.com.  
No fee is usually required, however, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.  
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity or for further information.  
Time limit to respond - We try to respond to all legitimate requests within 30 days. Occasionally it may take us longer than 30 days if your request is particularly complex or you have made several requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

## CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES

This notice was last updated on 24 May 2018. We may update it from time to time. If we make changes to this notice we will notify you by updating it on our website.  
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

## COOKIES

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site.  
A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.  
You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. 

We use the following cookies: 

· **Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.  
· **Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.  
· **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).  
· **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:

Host | Name | Purpose | Expiry | Description  
---|---|---|---|---  
| nowelcomepopup | Performance | 6 months | With the launch of our Kurt Geiger Welcome program. This cookie is used to determine whether a visitor had been displayed with the welcome program popup windows previously.  
| CATEGORY_INFO | Performance | Browser closed | When browsing any of our product listing pages, this cookie remembers what filtering was applied on previous page views, to enhance the browsing experience.  
| VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie remembers what products were viewed by the customer on previous page views, to enhance the browsing experience  
| CART | Performance | 1 hour | A unique identifier that is associated with a customer's shopping bag is kept in this cookie. This is basically so that our website has got access to this information at all times throughout a customer's visit.  
| persistent_shopping_cart | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie remembers what products were added into your shopping basket, to enhance the browsing experience  
| CUSTOMER | Performance | 1 hour | Once a user is logged in, this cookie remembers a unique identifier associated with that customer's session, so that the website has access to it at all times throughout the customer's visit.  
| CUSTOMER_INFO | Performance | 1 hour | Once a user is logged in, this cookie remembers a unique identifier associated with that customer's group that they have been placed in, so that the website has access to it at all times throughout the customer's visit.  
| CUSTOMER_AUTH | Performance | 1 hour | This cookie remembers your login details to keep you logged in when returning to the site, to enhance the browsing experience  
| VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS_INFO | Performance | Browser Closed | When Browsing Any Of Our Product Listing Pages, This Cookie Remembers What Filtering Was Applied On Previous Page Views, To Enhance The Browsing Experience.  
| WISHLIST | Performance | 1 hour | This cookie remembers a unique identifier associated with a customer's wishlist, if the customer had created a wishlist during a particular visit. This is so that the website has got access to it at all times throughout the customer's visit.  
| WISHLIST_CNT | Performance | 1 hour | This cookie remembers a unique identifier associated with the amount of items in a customer's wishlist, if the customer had created a wishlist during a particular visit. This is so that the website has got access to it at all times throughout the customer's visit.  
| frontend | Performance | 1 hour | This cookie contains a unique identifier relating to a customer's session on our website. This allows the website to provide continuity between customer visits.  
| Stc112126 | Performance | Browser closed | This is the third party cookie used to store all the other cookie data in a shortened form. The Cookie’s name has the site ID in it.  
| COUNTRY_BANNER_HIDE | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie determines if you have already closed the international site switching notification bar. This is used for switching between our international sites.  
| is_returning | Performance | 5 years | This cookie is used to remember if the customer has visited the site before and will note you as a returning visitor or new visitor.  
| CACHED_FRONT_FORM_KEY | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie ensures onsite forms are not submitted by someone outside of the website.  
| LAST_CATEGORY | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to store the customers last visited category and notes the category identification number that was last viewed.  
| COUNTRY | Performance | 5 years | This cookie remembers which country the customer has selected from the on site country selector to ensure the customer has an optimum shopping experience e.g. displaying product and delivery prices in a relevant currency.  
| mp__utma | Performance | 2 years | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information.  
| mp__utmb | Performance | 30 minutes | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information.  
| mp__utmc | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information.  
| mp__utmz | Performance | 1 month | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information.  
| _ga | Performance | 2 years | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information  
| _gali | Performance | 1 minute | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information  
| _gat | Performance | 10 minutes | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor informations  
| _gat_rollup | Performance | 10 minutes | This cookie is used to enable the functionality provided by Google Analytics. This software allows us to analyse visitor information  
| vee24.testCookie | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat.  
| v24s_kurtgeiger | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| v24u_kurtgeiger | Performance | 10 years | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.autoNudgeRules | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.nudgeReceived.timeout | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.nudgeReceived.timestamp | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.numberOfNudgesShown | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.testCookie | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| vee24.userIsActive | Performance | Browser closed | This cookie is used to enable the online chat functionality and allows us to analyse the use of online chat  
| _ceg.s | Performance | 91 days | Track visitor sessions  
| _ceg.u | Performance | 91 days | Track visitors on our site  
| scarab.visitor | Performance | 365 days | This cookie is used to display personalised product recommendations on the page.  
| scarab.profile | Performance | 365 days | This cookie is used to display personalised product recommendations on the page.  
| scarab.mayAdd | Performance | 365 days | This cookie is used to display personalised product recommendations on the page.  
| mage-translation-storage | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| mage-translation-file-version | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| form_key | Functionality | 1 hour | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| mage-cache-storage | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| mage-cache-storage-section-invalidation | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| mage-cache-sessid | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| mage-banners-cache-storage | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| PHPSESSID | Functionality | 1 hour | Your session identifier on the server. Used to help make speed of webpage requests quicker and more efficient.  
| private_content_version | Functionality | 10 years | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| section_data_ids | Functionality | Session | Facilitates caching of content on the browser to make pages load faster.  
| _hjClosedSurveyInvites | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set once a visitor interacts with a Survey invitation modal popup (a modal popup is a type of internal site popup). It is used to ensure that the same invite does not re-appear if it has already been shown.  
| _hjDonePolls | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set once a visitor completes a poll using the Feedback Poll widget. It is used to ensure that the same poll does not re-appear if it has already been filled in.  
| _hjMinimizedPolls | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set once a visitor minimizes a Feedback Poll widget. It is used to ensure that the widget stays minimizes when the visitor navigates through our site.  
| _hjDoneTestersWidgets | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set once a visitor submits their information in the Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the same form does not re-appear if it has already been filled in.  
| _hjMinimizedTestersWidgets | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This cookie is set once a visitor minimizes a Recruit User Testers widget. It is used to ensure that the widget stays minimizes when the visitor navigates through our site.  
| _hjIncludedInSample | Performance | 365 days | Hotjar cookie. This session cookie is set to let Hotjar know whether that visitor is included in the sample which is used to generate funnels. Funnels are designed to help us identify where users may exit from our site – this can help us to improve the user experience in the future.  
| _cs_id | Targeting/Advertising | 395 days | This cookie contains ContentSquare’s user identifier. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
| _cs_s | Targeting/Advertising | 30 minutes | This cookie contains the number of pageviews within the running session for ContentSquare Solution. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
| _cs_vars | Targeting/Advertising | Session | This cookie is used by ContentSquare to record custom variables. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
| _cs_ex | Targeting/Advertising | 30 days | This cookies is used by ContentSquare to exclude some visitors from the collection. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
| _cs_c | Targeting/Advertising | 395 days | This cookies is used by ContentSquare to save the user consent to be tracked. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
| _cs_optout | Targeting/Advertising | 1095 days | This cookies is used by ContentSquare to exclude some visitors from the collection. ContentSquare is a solution which aggregates usage and frequency data to improve user experience. Statistics created are anonymous. To view ContentSquare's privacy policy see <https://www.contentsquare.com/privacy-policy/>. To be excluded from this monitoring, please click here.  
.abmr.net | 01AI | Functionality | 365 days | Addthis share buttons  
.adnxs.com | anj | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Ads targeting cookie for AppNexus  
.adnxs.com | sess | Targeting/Advertising | < 1 day | Used to check if the user's browser supports cookies.  
.adnxs.com | uuid2 | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Run by AppNexus, a company that provides technology, data and analytics to help companies buy and sell online advertising. These cookies capture visitor information such as whether your browser is set to receive cookies and interest segments to provide you with personalised adverts when you visit other selected websites. They will also stop you seeing the same advert too many times, they collect information on what adverts you have seen, how recently they have been shown and how many total adverts you have been shown. To view AppNexus' privacy policy see <http://www.appnexus.com/platform-policy>.  
.adsrvr.org | TDID | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Registers a unique identification number that identifies a returning user's device. The identification number is used for targeted ads  
.adsrvr.org | TDCPM | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Registers a unique identification number that identifies a returning user's device. The identification number is used for targeted ads.  
.bing.com | MUID | Targeting/Advertising | 390 days | Allow user tracking  
.c.bing.com | MR | Targeting/Advertising | 180 days | Bing search/adwords tracking  
.c.bing.com | ANONCHK | Targeting/Advertising | < 1 day | Bing search/adwords tracking  
.casalemedia.com | CMID | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.casalemedia.com | CMDD | Targeting/Advertising | < 1 day | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.casalemedia.com | CMST | Targeting/Advertising | < 1 day | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.casalemedia.com | CMRUM3 | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.casalemedia.com | CMPS | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.casalemedia.com | CMSC | Targeting/Advertising | - | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.d16fk4ms6rqz1v.cloudfront.net | sc_test | Unknown | < 1 day | Used to manage and control media from our sites.  
.demdex.net | demdex | Targeting/Advertising | 180 days | Tracks behavioural data from our site.  
.doubleclick.net | drt | Targeting/Advertising | 235 days | Google Analytics  
.doubleclick.net | id | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Identifier for Google Analytics  
.dpclk.com | rmuid | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | This class consists entirely of inline methods to create and manipulate UUID's (universally unique identifier) via UUID library functions.  
.dpclk.com | __df_v4 | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Used in conjunction with Linkshare affiliate marketing.  
.dpm.demdex.net | dpm | Targeting/Advertising | 180 days | Tracks behavioural data from our site.  
.dsp.linksynergy.com | __df_v5 | Unknown | 365 days | Used in conjunction with Linkshare affiliate marketing.  
.facebook.com | datr | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | These cookies are used by the social networks to allow you to share any of our pages with your network - however nothing is shared without your explicit request to do so.  
.facebook.com | x-src | Targeting/Advertising | 235 days | These cookies allow the 'Like' button to work so that the user can share content from the website on their own Facebook page  
.facebook.com | fr | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Contains browser and user unique ID combinaton, used for targeted advertising  
.facebook.com | lu | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | These cookies allow the 'Like' button to work so that the user can share content from the website on their own Facebook page  
.facebook.com | locale | Targeting/Advertising | 242 days | Keeps track of the language by means of a cookie so the language is preserved no matter of the user is logged in or not. It also works for recurring users.  
.google.co.uk | SAPISID | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Used by Google to store user preferences and information of Google maps  
.google.co.uk | HSID | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Used by Google in combination with SID to verify Google user account and most recent login time  
.google.co.uk | SID | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | This cookie is used by Google in combination with HSID to verify a Google user account and most recent login time  
.google.co.uk | PREF | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Stores user preference and can be used to personalise ads on google searches  
.google.co.uk | NID | Targeting/Advertising | 418 days | Used by Google to store user preferences and information of Google maps  
.google.co.uk | SSID | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Used by Google to store user preferences and information of Google maps  
.google.co.uk | APISID | Targeting/Advertising | 965 days | Used by Google to store user preferences and information of Google maps  
.google.com | NID | Targeting/Advertising | 418 days | Used by Google to store user preferences and information of Google maps  
.mathtag.com | HRL8 | Targeting/Advertising | 28 days | 128-bit number used to identify information in computer systems  
.mathtag.com | mt_mop | Targeting/Advertising | 30 days | This cookie is generated by double-click floodlight tags. This cookie holds random strings.  
.mathtag.com | uuidc | Targeting/Advertising | 393 days | Collects data on the user's visits to the website, such as what pages have been loaded. The registered data is used for targeted ads.  
.mathtag.com | mt_misc | Targeting/Advertising | 30 days | Addthis share buttons  
.mathtag.com | uuid | Targeting/Advertising | 393 days | 128-bit number used to identify information in computer systems  
.mediaforge.com | uID | Unknown | 365 days | User identifier and login time tracking  
.mediaforge.com | pID | Unknown | 365 days | Stores details about the traffic source.  
.mediaforge.com | cID | Unknown | 365 days | Stores details about the traffic source.  
.mediaforge.com | uid3 | Unknown | 365 days | Stores details about the traffic source.  
.mookie1.com | id | Targeting/Advertising | 395 days | The cookie is generated b double-click floodlight tags. This cookie holds random string values.  
.mookie1.com | mdata | Targeting/Advertising | 395 days | Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user's device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
.nr-data.net | JSESSIONID | Performance | session | This cookie keeps information about your browsing history for the duration of that session.  
.pixel.rubiconproject.com | rpx | Targeting/Advertising | 30 days | This cookie is generated by double-click floodlight tags. This cookie holds random strings.  
.pubmatic.com | KRTBCOOKIE_27 | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | This cookie is generated by double-click floodlight tags. This cookie holds random strings.  
.pubmatic.com | PUBMDCID | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Used by PubMatic, Inc. a seller of aggregated publisher ad inventory from many websites. Many ad networks use proprietary technology and partner with data aggregators to target ads. Facilitating and / or engaging in 3rd party interest-based targeting.  
.pubmatic.com | KRTBCOOKIE_1029 | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Registers a unique ID that identifies the user's device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
.rd.linksynergy.com | mfuid | Unknown | 30 days | Linkshare affiliate tracking for commission based advertising.  
.rfihub.com | smd | Targeting/Advertising | 390 days | Google Analytics to analyse the use of this website  
.rfihub.com | u | Targeting/Advertising | 390 days | Collects data on user visits to the website, such as what pages have been accessed. The registered data is used to categorise the user's interest and demographic profiles in terms of re-sales for targeted marketing.  
.rfihub.com | rud | Targeting/Advertising | 390 days | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.rfihub.com | eud | Targeting/Advertising | 390 days | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.rfihub.com | euds | Targeting/Advertising | session | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.rfihub.com | ruds | Targeting/Advertising | session | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.rubiconproject.com | put_* | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.rubiconproject.com | rpb | Targeting/Advertising | 30 days | This cookie is generated by double-click floodlight tags. This cookie holds random strings.  
.rubiconproject.com | khaos | Targeting/Advertising | 182 days | Registers anonymous user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
.s.thebrighttag.com | bt3 | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Used by the social sharing platform AddThis to keep a record of parts of the site that has been visited in order to recommend other parts of the site  
.serving-sys.com | u2 | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | Providing multi-platform targeted advertising services.  
.serving-sys.com | ActivityInfo2 | Targeting/Advertising | 90 days | These cookies are placed by Media Mind. This information enables us to make our marketing activity more relevant.  
.yahoo.com | B | Targeting/Advertising | 731 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's website visits, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded. The registered data is used to categorise the users' interest and demographical profiles with the purpose of customising the website content depending on the visitor.  
lsmfcs.rd.linksynergy.com | SERVERID | Targeting/Advertising | session | used for load balancing. Identifies the server that delivered the last page to the browser  
recommender.scarabresearch.com | s | Targeting/Advertising | session | Emarsys email marketing tracking.  
recommender.scarabresearch.com | cdv | Targeting/Advertising | 365 days | Emarsys email marketing tracking.  
.rlcdn.com | Ck1 | Targeting/Advertising | 179 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.rlcdn.com | rlas3 | Targeting/Advertising | 179 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.rlcdn.com | rtn1-z | Targeting/Advertising | 179 days | Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
.mention-me.com | mm_id | Targeting/Advertising | 1825 days | permanent cookie used to track order completions on our site which allow us to tie a referral reward back to you  
.mention-me.com | PHPSESSID | Targeting/Advertising | session | temporary token which allows us to keep track of your session when using the site
